Good afternoon. Today we have as a guest
Здравствуйте Сегодня у нас в гостях
Dmytro Savchenko, the head of the
Дмитрий Савченко руководитель издательства
Iron Dad publishing house and a fighter of the da
железный папа и боец ​​подразделения да
Vinci unit of the Ukrainian volunteer corps.
Винчи добровольческого украинского корпуса
did you come to the point where you came to the point of
Почему вы пришли к тому как вы пришли к
publishing such non-standard
чтобы выдавать вот такую ​​нестандартную
literature for modern times,
можно сказать литературу для современности
actually standard literature, it probably
собственно стандартную литературу видимо и
doesn’t make sense to publish it because it was
нет смысла выдавать потому что она была
published there during Soviet times, actually
издана там в советское время собственно
standard literature or If we talk
стандартная литература или Если говорить
about the present standard literature, it is
о настоящем стандартной литературы то
grant literature which  actually
это грантовая литература, которая собственно
reflects the agenda that is
отражает ту повестку дня, которая
imposed on Ukraine from the outside with
навязывается в Украине извне
the help of some financial resources. We
помощью каких-то финансовых ресурсов
decided to go underground and, as it
решили идти undergrounding по пути и как
were,
бы еще
from the beginning of our existence, we determined
с начала своего существования мы определили
the course that we specialize in
курс что мы специализируемся на
anti-Russian topics. That is, our
антироссийские тематике То есть наш
main vector is everything that  it is connected
главный вектор – это вот все что связано
with the fact that we should [ __ ] in the soul of the katsaps, go
с тем чтобы насрать в душу кацапам пойти в
against their narratives,
разрез с их нарративами
refute their historical lies,
опровергнуть их историческую ложь
mainly, well, and sow an absolutely
главным образом Ну и посеять абсолютно
healthy humanistic, intelligent,
здоровый гуманистический интеллигентный
Russophobic mood,
русофобское настроение
if the Soviet school often depicted an
если бы часто у нас Советская школа
intellectual person as such a
изобразила человека интеллектуала как такового
nerd, withered in glasses, so
ботана зачахло в очках да
your publishing house gives  another point of view,
ваше же издательство так дает другой взгляд
so an intellectual is not just some
так что интеллектуал – это не просто какой-то
kind of scumbag, it is a person. I
такой дров так а это человек
apologize for interrupting our publishing house, it
Извиняюсь перебью наше издательство оно
made it clear and actually showed that an
дало понять и показало собственно то, что
intellectual is a person who mainly
интеллектуал - это человек преимущественно
uses such objects.
использует такие предметы
in
путешествую по фронтам по
all kinds of combat locations,
всяческим боевым локациям всегда со мной
my loyal girlfriend is always with me, so I
моя верная подружка поэтому я дикую
apologize profusely for interrupting you with a
извиняюсь за то, что перебил тебя на е-е
question, so I pass the baton on to you so that
вопрос потому передаю тебе эстафету чтобы
you can finish your question. I am attentive. It is
ты закончил свой вопрос Я внимательно
cool that there is a lively conversation.  it's
классно живущий разговор Я не люблю в глазу
just
такие знаешь как этот бюрократический просто
communication, but when you're alive, it's
общение так а вот когда жива – это
cool, so if you want to
классно поэтому если хочется перебить
interrupt, it's an advantage. I also like to interrupt, yes.
преимущество Я тоже люблю перебивать да То
Look, the Soviet school depicted an
смотри Советская школа она изображала
intellectual as such a nerd, yes, if you
интеллектуал как такового ботана так и если
look at your publishing house, yes. That is, all
смотреть ваше издательство да есть все
books about a strong personality are about a
книги о сильной личности да о
person. That's the name itself  iron dad,
человека Вот и собственное название железный папа
tell me why this particular one was chosen, and
да расскажите Почему именно такую ​​выбрали и
if we take the same Pythagoras, he
Если мы возьмем тот же Пифагор так
was a champion of punches, he had a
был чемпионом по кулачным у него была
Pythagorean school that the then Berkut
пифагорецкая школа, которую тогдашний Беркут
took by storm, you can say it like this. Do
брал штурмом можно так сказать так вот Как
you think an
вы считаете
intellectual should be a greyhound or calm?
интеллектуал должен быть долбой или спокойным
must be girded with Olympic
должен быть опоясанным олимпийским
peace, I am sure that an intellectual is a
спокойствием уверенным тебе и интеллектуал это
person of the noble kind,
человек на самом деле шляхетского сорта
because he must always stand up for his
потому что он всегда должен постоять за свои
views, for his values
взгляды на свои ценности
with his fists, and in battle he must cherish
с кулаками и в бою он должен лелеять
weapons, possess some elements of
оружие владеть собственно каким-то элементами
combat, because an intellectual is a person who
боя потому что интеллектуал человек который
enriches himself with internal principles. And
обогащается внутренними принципами
she  draws,
она черпает
let's say, some meanings from books,
скажем какие-то смыслы из книг их
transforms them in oneself and forms one's
трансформирует в себе и формирует свою
worldview position, uh, to have a worldview
мировоззренческую позицию е-е иметь мировоззренческую
position is a very expensive pleasure in our time,
позицию это в наше время очень дорогое
because sooner or later, a
удовольствие потому что рано или поздно На
scumbag will appear on your path who will
твоему пути появится почварь которая
want to go against your worldview
захочет пойти вопреки твоему мировоззренческому
position, refute it, humiliate it
позиции опровергнуть ее унизить
in view of the fact that in modern
учитывая что ну, если бы современному
society, if the mechanisms of respect are
обществе если бы механизмы уважения
very muted, that's why when it comes to
ну очень притуманены поэтому когда речь идет о
some principles, collective, corporate,
какие принципы коллективные корпоративные
worldview, ideological, I would say so,
мировоззренческие идеологические я бы так сказал
here it is necessary to pay attention to the fact that these
то здесь нужно учитывать то что за эти
principles must be stood by force.
принципы нужно стоять силой
Therefore, it is necessary to develop the actual and physical
Поэтому нужно развивать собственно и физические
direction of work  carry weapons
направление работы над собой лелеять оружие
and read books, these components
и читать книги вот эти компоненты они
actually give a complete image of an
собственно и дают целостный образ
intellectual of our time and actually a
интеллектуала нашего времени и собственно
harmonious person who, in principle, should
гармоничного человека имеющего в принципе
reflect some correct
отражать какие-то вот правильные
Ukrainian meanings. In other words, it should not
украинские смыслы То есть это не должен
be a shiver in the glasses. I do not want to
быть там дрожь в очках Я не хочу
choose people
выбрать людей
with bad eyesight
с плохим зрением
instead, it should be a person of a
но это должен быть человек
sports type who stands up for his
спортивного типа которая стоит за своих
fellows, who, say, are more such
собратьев, которые скажи, являются более такими
cabinet
кабинетными
researchers and who share our
исследователями и разделяющими нашу
position of such people, too, in abundance, therefore, if
позицию таких тоже достаточно потому
good should have fists and be armed to the
добро должно иметь кулаки и быть до
teeth, it is precisely from this that we
зубов вооруженным собственно от этого мы
were repelled
отталкивались
not by the physical state, but by the spiritual, so that is  a
не физическое состояние а духовное так есть
person can be a
человек может быть
person can be thin Yes but have a
человек может быть худеньким Да но мать
fiery spirit can be large but
воспалительный дух может быть крупной но
be afraid to say something to someone so eyes so
бояться что-то кому-то сказать так глаза да
absolutely and at the expense of the publishing house in our country
абсолютно и на счет издательства у нас
now a lot of Ukrainian publishers
сейчас очень много украинских издателей
are crying that Ukrainian literature is not
плачут что украинская литература не
in demand and so on and so on
пользуется спросом и так далее
How are you in  Are you surviving in this sea? Is there a demand
Как вы в этом море выживаете Есть ли спрос
for your literature? Yes, where do you get
на вашу литературу Так откуда вы берете
funding from, or is the funding itself, does it
финансирование или на самом финансировании
pay off
окупается ли оно Планируете ли вы
?  to a
ваши планы и видение этого рынка Ну я
certain extent, they cheat on Ukrainian literature, we
украинскую литературу они в определенной степени
have a real problem in Ukrainian society if we take the
обществе действительно проблема если брать
period before the Great War, there is a problem that the
период до Великой войны есть проблема что
consequences of the colonial influence of the Russian
последствия колониального влияния Российского
Empire on us were quite influential. And indeed, the reading culture
империи на нас И действительно культура чтения
would be quite recessive,
она бы была столь достаточно рецессивной
recessive due to external influences, yes
рецессивной через внешнее воздействие да
were nurtured Some kind of stupidity was
плекались Какая-то тупость плекалась такая
nurtured in a person, opportunism
воспитывалась в человеке конъюнктурщина
was nurtured, conformism was nurtured in a person,
воспитывалась воспитывающимся в человеке и
but in principle,
питался конформизм но в принципе
Ukrainians, for these 30 years of independence,
украинцы вот за эти 30 лет Независимости
they showed such small progress, and
они показали такие маленькие продвижения И
showed their desire to move forward,
показали Ну свое стремление идти вперед как
but the number of
не крути Но у нас количество
reading people has increased  in society,
читающих людей выросло в обществе
I will not say that these are some kind of leap-like
я не скажу что это какой-то скачкообразный
changes, but still there are positive
изменения но все же положительная
dynamics, but when it comes to the
динамика но когда речь уже идет о
period of the great war, I think that
период большой войны Я думаю что
Ukrainian literature has a great future, and this is the
украинской литературы большое будущее и
whole historical drama of
этот вот е-е весь исторический драматизм
which we are witnesses and participants.
свидетелями и участниками которого мы являемся он
will help us to make
только поспособствует нам в том чтобы
Ukrainian literature reach the world
украинская литература вышла на мировой
level, these events create a very
уровень эти события они создают нам очень
convenient springboard for us to rise now in
удобный трамплин для подъема сейчас в
the world. I think that the demand for Ukrainian
мире Я думаю что спрос на украинский
literature is the interest in Ukrainian
литературу интерес к украинскому
literature. Well, it is incredible that the culture of
литературы Ну невероятно это культура
Ukraine is packed in geometric
украинской упаковки в геометрических
progressions in geometric progressions, that's why
прогрессиях в геометрической прогрессии
I  I am also
да я тоже
forced to state that before the
вынужден констатировать то, что там до
Great War and, in particular, before the
Великой войны а в том числе и до
Revolution of Dignity, the
Революции Достоинства
situation with reading books and the
е-е ситуация с чтением книг и вот
growth of the audience actually
собственно е-е прирост аудитории
took place in such microscopic
происходил достаточно такими микроскопическими
steps that it was such a snail's pace, it was a
шагами Так это такое улиточное продвижение
very
е-е это очень такой
slow, slow development  of
замедленное замедленное развитие
our critical thinking, but the
нашего критического мышления но
first stage and the first prerequisite for
первый этап и первую предпосылку для
the growth of the reading audience was formed by the
рост читающего аудитории сформировала
Revolution of Dignity, and the second one itself. This is
Революция Достоинства а второе уже собственное Я
how I see what is formed by the great war and how
да вижу что формирует е-е великая война и как
not to be cool, but still history and
не крути но все же история и
historical recitations, historical drama,
исторические перипетии исторические драматизм
tragedies, they force a person to look
трагедии они заставляют человека заглянуть
into  the depth of oneself and look for meanings there with the
в глубину себя и искать там смыслы смыслы
help of books with the help of
с помощью книг с помощью
reflection and this is all in the aggregate it has a
рефлексии и это все в совокупном счете
positive effect on our
оно положительно сказывается на нашей
books and other matters in general on the
книге и другом деле вообще на
Ukrainian noosphere on the Ukrainian
украинской ноосфере на украинском
intellectual environment that is why we
интеллектуальной среде поэтому да мы
have broken cities we have I do not
имеем разломленные города мы имеем Я не
know there are problems
знаю там проблемы
with many  household issues and
со многими бытовыми вопросами и в
many people there
многих людей там
have destroyed houses, some will be left without
разгромленные дома кто-то останется без
relatives, some will be left without housing, without
родственников кто-то остался без жилья без
property, but all these wanderings, all these
имущества но эти все скитания эти все
sufferings, they
страдания они
contribute to the fact that a person
способствуют тому, что человек
wants to rummage in himself, wants to find an
хочет коперситься в себе хочет найти
answer to the question Why is this
ответ на вопрос Почему да
happening And this is already a kind of
происходит А это уже своеобразно
spring to  for a person to look for
пружиной к тому, чтобы человек искал
some kind of Truth, for example, in history
какой-то Правды например в исторических
books. And why, in the end, the Katsapas
книгах А почему в конце концов на нас от [ __ ]
attacked us? There is probably some prehistory of our
напали наверное есть какая-то предыстория наших
long and difficult situations,
таких длительных и сложных ситуаций
not eight years there, but why are the Poles
не восемь лет там, а почему нам поляки
helping us? And let's look at the
помогают А давайте посмотрим на
phenomenon of the Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth.  it
феномен Речи Посполитой возможно
was so bad
Посполитая не такая уж плохая была и
that there really were separate stages of history
чтобы действительно были отдельные этапы истории
when we lived there with Poles and Lithuanians
когда мы там с поляками с литовцами жили
quite peacefully and
достаточно мирно и
harmoniously coexisted within the boundaries of the same
гармонично сосуществовали в пределах одной
state institution, so actually
е-е государственного института потому вот собственно
all these events force us to look for
эти все события они заставляют нас искать
answers
ответ
to the questions of the present, the present
на вопрос сегодняшнего дня
is very  a positive effect is a very positive
это очень положительный эффект очень положительный
consequence and I am more sure that
следствие и я больше уверен что
Ukrainian books and Ukrainian
украинской книги и украинской
literature have a great future and it is already
литературы есть большое будущее и оно уже
being created before our eyes and we are already becoming
творится на наших глазах и мы уже становимся
co-participants of this future right
соучастниками этой будущей прямо
today,
сегодня
but of the publications that you have published, your
вот из тех изданий, которые вы выдали ваше
publishing house can name one or two
издательство можете назвать там одну-две
they are probably more proud
которыми они больше гордитесь
here. It should be noted that the
наверное здесь Следует отметить
Ukrainian-language version of the book by Dzhihar
украиноязычную версию книги джихара
Dudayev is here, I will resort to a certain
Дудаева здесь я прибегну к определенному такому
explanation in more detail that this is the book of the
объяснение более подробного что это книга
Great Chechen
Большого чеченского
leader, the head of
лидера
the state, the founder, I would
руководителя государства основателя я бы да
say so, or the resuscitator of the Ichkerian
сказал или реаниматора ичкерийской
state, and she. This book was published for
государства и она Эта книга Она вышла
the first time, that is, to our  edition, there
впервые в мир есть до нашего издания не
were no books by Jahar Dudayev, there were
существовало книг джахара Дудаева существовали
books about him as a bright and
книги о нем как о яркой и
enchanting personality, as a
феерическую личность как о
statesman and a historical figure, but it was
государствотворца и исторического деятеля но
his texts that the
именно его текстов
reader did not have in his hands, yes He
читатель не имел у себя под руками да Он не
could not get acquainted with that
мог познакомиться с тем
printed material, you took it,
печатная материал вы взяли оригиналы его
then they said it  speeches and
тогда сказали его речи и
transformed them into texts,
трансформировали в их текстах
edited them, combed their hair, well, in
отредактировали причесали ну такая в
principle, we had an interesting idea.
принципе у нас Интересная идея возникла Мы эту
Dzhokhar Dudayev wrote this idea to the introduction, you
идею вводика написал джохар Дудаев это вы
actually transcribed it.
транскрибировали его фактически
So we made such a transformation and
Так мы сделали такую ​​трансформацию и
simply engraved his word in the text on
просто запечатлели его слово в тексте в
paper,
бумаги
and actually thanks to this, it appeared
и собственно благодаря этому появилась
first of all, it is the first book by Dzhokhar
во-первых первая книга самого Джохара
Dudayev himself, and secondly, it is
Дудаева А во-вторых она
something most interesting. It was published in a
что-то самое интересное Она вышла в свет
non-Chichen language, and even more so not in
на нечиченском языке и тем более не
Russian, but in Ukrainian, and that is why I
на русском а именно на украинском языке и
believe that with this book we have reached a
поэтому я считаю что этой книгой мы достигли
certain historical level, in fact I am
определенной исторической планки чем собственно Я
proud of the second project that would  I wanted to
горжусь второй проект который бы я хотел
point out that the book of our
отметить это книга нашей
Latin Aeneid, we took Ivan
латиночной Энеиды мы взяли Ивана
Kotlyarevsky
Котляревского
and separated it
а отделяли от него
from the standard edition of the more
от стандартного издания такого более
ordinary, shabby traditional edition of
обычного трусливого традиционного издания
Kotlyarevsky, which we met at
Котляревского с которым мы знакомились в
school, and separated the illustrative
школе отграничили иллюстративный
series on which Bazilevich worked.
ряд над которым работал Базилевич То есть
that means on
казаки которые в шароварах значит на
bare torsos as ultras and we
обнаженных торсах как ультрасы и мы
simply replaced
просто-напросто заменили
this illustrative chain with already
эта иллюстративная цепочка уже
modernized Cossacks, we had ATO
усовремененными казаками это у нас были
soldiers at that time the book was published
воины АТО на тот момент книга вышла
If I am not mistaken in the 18th or in the 18th
Если я не ошибаюсь в 18-м или в 18-м
year and that is why they are such modern Cossacks
году и потому там такие современные казаки
in disarmaments in bulletproof vests in
они в разгрузках в бронежилетах в
tactical tales with
тактических сказках
modern weapons and we actually
современным оружием и мы собственно
extrapolated all the characters, positive and negative, on the reality of what is today,
экстраполировали на реалии чего-то настоящего
that is, negative characters, we
то есть отрицательные персонажи это у нас там
had uh, Moscow priests there. It was easy to
были е-е московские попы Там легко было
recognize Onufry uh, well, this lie of the
узнать Онуфрия е-е ну этого лжен
Metropolitan who is in the Lavra  is the
Митрополита, который в Лавре сидит е-е
text of the Aeneid sitting or only the illustrations now
текст Энеиды или только иллюстрации сейчас
I want to
я дотекстуальной составляющей передок хочу
complete my own
завершить собственно
explanation of the visual part of this
свое объяснение визуальной части этой
unsurpassed book with the pre-textual component of the Aeneid or just the illustrations, this beautiful
непревзойденной книги этого прекрасного
colorful edition of the screamingly
колоритного издания
beautiful I praise myself Because
кричащего прекрасного сам себя хвалю Бо
no one will approve
никто не прихвалит
if you don't love yourself then
если сам себя не любишь то тебя полюбит
absolutely
абсолютно
negative characters will love you  there were some,
отрицательные персонажи у нас там были какие-то
we compared all of them with the
мы их всех сравнили с там
representatives of the then Party of
представителями там тогдашней Партии
Regions or that upszh there. Lukashenko is
Регионов или тот упсж там Лукашенко у нас
present there. That is, it is precisely in
там присутствуют есть это именно в
the administrations and vice versa,
администрациях и наоборот положительные
our positive friends are our Ukrainian
друзья наши украинские
friends of Ukraine. They were
собственно друзья Украины Это были
also active people there, you could
также действующие лица там можно было
recognize certain figures of Polish
узнать определенных деятелей польского
politics  Well, in general, we went on
политикума Ну вот В общем мы пошли на
such an adventure, we modernized the
такую ​​авантюру сделали модернизацию
illustrative component of the Aeneid, but what is
иллюстративной составляющей Энеиды но Что
most important, if we go to the question of the
самое главное если перейти уже к вопросу
textual part, then we
текстуальной части то мы
simply adopted and gave up the Cyrillic alphabet
взяли просто и отказались от кириллицы
and published this Aeneid in Ukrainian
и на и выдали эту енеиду именно на украинском
Latin, we took as a basis the
латинкой мы взяли за основу это
alphabetic system of Ivan Luchuk such  I would like to say that
алфавитную систему Ивана лучука такой я бы
there are a few Latin women,
несколько есть латинок
in fact there are a huge number of them, and
на самом деле огромное количество и среди
internal strategies are going on among Latin students,
латинщиков происходит внутренние
of which there are
стратегии которыми
not many,
не так много но мы находимся в этом
but we are in this camp. At the moment, it is very difficult for us to find our way in their internal polemics and discussions, hates and losses, but in principle we support this basic
но мы в принципе поддерживаем Вот эту
fundamental idea about  the fact that
базовую фундаментальную идею о том, что в
Ukraine needs its own Latin Alphabetic
Украине нужна своя латиновая Алфавитная
system because even Cyrillic countries
система потому что даже кириллические страны
and there are not so many of them left. So,
а их осталось не так много.
if you look at the map of the
если посмотреть на карту
geographical map of Ukraine that
географическую карту Украины
uses the Cyrillic alphabet, the
пользуются именно кириллицей
Cyrillic alphabet is mainly Russia and
кириллица это вот преимущественно это Россия и
Belarus, Ukraine, Bulgaria, Macedonia, the Serbs, the
Беларусь Украина Болгария Македония
Serbs have almost moved  in the
Серби Сербы почти перешли уже на
Latin alphabet, they
латинку у них кириллица
use the Cyrillic alphabet only in official
используется только в официальном
paperwork, that is, when you go to a
делопроизводстве то есть когда заходишь в
Serbian bookstore somewhere in the Serbian
сербский книжный магазин где-то ну сербских
populated areas of the city, you see that
населенных пунктах города Видишь там что
if a commercial book, an art book
если бы коммерческая книга художественная книга
is published in the Serbian Latin alphabet, and
кажется сербской латинкой и а
instead, some normative legal acts
а какие-то нормативно-правовые акты
or some state
или там ну где государственные какие-то там
Law documents there are actually
Документы законы они Ну действительно
published in Cyrillic, and in Bulgaria, the
публикуются именно кириллицей, а в Болгарии
Cyrillic alphabet remains in the dominant
там кириллица остается на господствующих
positions, but but, despite everything, there
но но при этом всем есть
is still a version of the Bulgarian
существует все же версия болгарской
Latin alphabet, and the Bulgarians do not perceive it as a
латинки и болгары это не воспринимают как
threat to national security, as a betrayal of
угрозу национальной безопасности как измену
historical principles.
исторических принципов
I will finish now and  here it is actually very
я я сейчас довершу и здесь собственно очень
embarrassing for Ukrainians because we
стыдно становится за украинцев, потому что у нас
do not have our own alphabetical system and we
нет своей алфавитной системы и мы
use
пользуемся
transliteration, that is, we still
транслитерацию есть все равно мы
use Latin letters, a
используем латинские буквы
banal example is
банальный пример – это
Ukrainian passports and foreign passports. Yes,
украинские паспорта да зарубежные Да да
instead of
вот вместо того чтобы у украинских
writing our Ukrainians' surnames in foreign passports,
загранпаспортах писать наши же
Ukrainians  er,
фамилия украинцев наших е-е
we write transliteration in Latin, well,
латинкой мы пишем транслитерацию ну
this is the level of a
такой уровень
humanitarian approach to
собственно гуманитарного подхода к
solving such issues. Well, he
решение таких вопросов Ну он где-то
places us somewhere on the
располагает нас
same level as
на одном на на одной планке с
African countries, and this is something that
африканскими странами и это очень нас
worries us about this topic because, first of all,
как-то беспокоит эта тема, потому что во-первых
transliteration does not reflect the
транслитерация она не отражает
phonetic nature  in the Ukrainian language, and
фонетическую природу на украинском языке
secondly, even if the Latin script did not gain
во-вторых Пусть бы и латинка не приобрела бы
immediate popularity in Ukraine, there
одномоментной популярности в Украине
should still be a Ukrainian version of the
все же должна быть украинская версия
Latin script, just as there is a Bulgarian version of the
латинки как есть болгарская версия
alphabetic Latin writing system, that is why we are
алфавитной латинической системы писания
pedaling this problem, we are
поэтому мы эту проблематику педалируем мы
facing huge
подвергаемся огромному
opposition in Ukrainian society,
сопротивление в украинском обществе на
unfortunately among  there are many Ukrainians who carry
жаль среди украинцев много таких носителей
inert ideas, there is a lot of hate against us, what they
инертных идей очень много хейта на нас
say is that we are
что мол мы значит
alienating from the Ukrainian
отчуждаем от значит украинского
present, our deep
настоящее наших глубокие
roots, cutting off the Ukrainian deep
корни отсекаем украинский глубокий
Cyrillic culture from our soil,
кириллическую культуру от нашей почвы и
and so on. And so on, I often like to
так далее И так далее я часто люблю
answer these opponents.
отвечать этим оппонентам Ну простым
when
элементарным доказательством что господа Ну когда
you switched to Arabic numerals, you didn't
вы перешли на арабские цифры вы же не
become a one-time Adam, yes,
стали одномоментными адами да вам
Arabic numerals do not prevent you from continuing to be
арабские цифры не мешают дальше быть
Ukrainians, but in fact,
украинцами но на них действительно на этих
no arguments will work for these people, this is
людей не срабатывают никакие аргументы
more of a populist topic because the
больше такая популистическая тема потому что
majority of fellow citizens who come to
большинство сограждан приходящих в
this Latin language gossip the whole discussion they
этот латиночный Трач всю дискуссию они
normally they do not distinguish,
нормально не отличают
let's say, font from
скажем шрифт от
orthography and from the alphabet, they
орфографии и от алфавита они
call the Latin alphabet a font, you understand,
латинку называют шрифтом ну понимаете
yes. That is, these are such absolutely
да То есть это такие абсолютно
unworldly punctuations that immediately reveal an
несусветные проколы, которые сразу обнаруживают
incompetent approach in a person. A person,
в человеке некомпетентный подход человек не
having no idea about the depth of this discussion
имея представление о глубине этой дискуссии
about the depth of this issue, enters into an
о глубине этого вопроса вступает в
argument and there is more in  to this dispute,
спор и там больше в этом споре
let's say, gives some kind of emotional evaluations rather than
скажем дает эмоциональные какие-то оценки чем
constructive
конструктивные
logical arguments. By the way, I also often
логические аргументы Я кстати вот тоже часто
think about the issue of the Latin language, but I'm not
задумываюсь о вопросах латинки но не есть
such a battering ram of this idea, but I don't
таким каким-то тараном этой идеи, но не
see anything wrong with it. So, for example,
вижу в этом ничего плохого так
let's take Turkey.
например возьмем Турция так у них
writing, if I'm not mistaken, they switched to the
письмо если не ошибаюсь так перешли на
Latin script. Did the Turks leave their
латинку И что там турки оставили свои
identity there or something? No, it's normal and in
идентичность или что Нет так нормально и в
principle we integrate into the Western world, yes, the
принципе мы интегрируемся в западный мир
alphabet.  there
нас глаголица была там кириллица Да будет
will be no harm to a Latin person, but yes, you are right, you said that
будет Но Да есть вот вы правильно сказали
Ukrainians are so inertial, and in principle, it
украинцы такие инерционные и в принципе.
would be better not to change so that it would be as it
если бы лучше не менять так, чтобы было как
was. Well, it seems to me that it is still a
было Ну мне кажется это все равно
question. It may not be a year, two or three, but let's
вопрос Просто может не года двух трех а
say that we are still civilized
скажем цивилизационно мы все равно
let's come to the Latin language because we are
придем к латинке так как мы
integrating into this Western world, but
интегрируемся в этот западный мир но
here it is interesting that we brought it up, and here you
вот сюда интересно там мы подняли а вот вы
personally write your own poems, let's say.
лично е-е пишете свои скажем стихи
That's how I see, they wrote Valentine's Day poems in
Да я вижу писали валентинку стихи
Latin. That's how I wrote and even published
латинкой Так писал и даже издавал в
several books in which there are separate poems that  er, they are
нескольких книгах есть отдельные поэзии, которые е-е
actually published in the
собственно опубликованы именно
Latin alphabet.
латиночной алфавитом
Well, I will say that
Ну я скажу так что
I don’t
непосредственно на письме я мало
use the Latin alphabet directly in writing, although I
использую латинку хотя там я
used the Latin alphabet for quite a long time, that is, that’s the
довольно-таки долгое время вел свой
position I used to enter in the Latin alphabet about 3-4 years ago,
позиция была я где-то лет 3-4 ввел
but
латинкой но
in the end, people  they do not respond to the Latin script, and this
в конце концов, люди не реагируют на латиницу и это
led to a decrease in the audience,
привело к уменьшению аудитории
accordingly, I was not able to recommend any
соответственно я не смог рекомендовать какие-то
meanings, for me it is not a problem to switch to the
смыслы для меня не проблема перейти на
Latin script, it is important that we are now laying
латинку важно что мы сейчас закладываем
the foundation of Latin written culture,
фундамент латиночной письменной культуры
that is, Ukrainian Latin
то есть именно на украинском латинском
written culture, book culture,
письменной культуры книжной культуры
that is, it is also very important and we have it  we do
то есть и это очень важно и мы это имеем
not regret investing money in these projects.
не сожалеем вкладывать в эти проекты деньги
Let them not even return to us
Пусть они даже к нам не возвращаются
in full, because in fact, I will be
в полном объеме потому что на самом деле буду
frank, there are not so many supporters of this idea
откровенных симпатиков этой идеи не так
in Ukrainian society.
тот много В украинском обществе
But I understand that this is an idea of ​​the future, and
Но я понимаю что это идея будущего к
Ukrainians will definitely come to it.  will happen later,
украинцы Но да это случится позже
therefore, in this sense, we are a little
поэтому мы в этом смысле немножко
ahead of events and act as
опережаем события и выступаем в роли
such cultural forwards to
таких культурологических форвардов
carry this mission to reach this cross is
нести эту миссию дотянуть этот крест
not an easy task,
довольно-таки не нелегкое дело
but
ну
despite this, I would like to open certain
Несмотря на это я бы хотел открыть там некоторые
maps there and share my idea that
карты и поделиться своим замыслом что
after the end of the war when  If
собственно по завершению войны когда
it is crowned with victory and there is an
она увенчается победой и появится
opportunity for me to return to life, I
возможность у меня вернуться в жизнь я
will definitely take up the
активнее возьмусь за
topic of Ukrainian Latin more actively, and there is even an
темой украинской латинки и есть даже
idea, my colleagues and I have already discussed it several times, to
идея мы с коллегами уже не раз ее
found a whole movement of a
обсуждали основать целое движение
public organization that would
общественной организации которая бы
pedal this issue and
педалировала этот вопрос и
expand the resonant space of this
расширяли резонансное пространство этой
problems, if I'm not mistaken, you
проблематики я вот если не ошибаюсь вы
published, in addition to Jahar Dudayev, Aslan
выдавали кроме джахара Дудаева Аслана
Maskhadov, it seems that they published a book,
массхадова кажется издавали книгу
published Zvyada Gamsukhurdia and many
издавали свяда гамсухурдиа и много
books by Korchinsky. Yes, I
книг корчинского Так я понимаю что вы
understand you. As far as I understand, you have long been from the community
Насколько я понимаю Вы давно из сообщества
that is so associated with Dmytro Korchinsky,
которая с Дмитрием Корчинским да
so I don't know if you were in a
ассоциирована так Я не знаю ли вы были в
brotherhood  were there not, but the fact that with Dmytro
братстве не были но то что с Дмитрием
this is always how much influence
постоянно этот вот насколько вот повлиял
Korchinsky had on you. How can you say?
Корчинский на вас Как вы можете сказать
You will
Вы
understand that, well, if Korchinsky and
поймете что ну если бы с корчинским из
Dmytro Oleksandrov are very
Дмитрием Александровым очень такие у нас
deep and long-standing relations, that is, in fact, I
глубокие и давние отношения то есть по существу я
got into the circle of Dmytro
прибился к среде Дмитрия
Oleksandrovich and more  well, from such a
Александровича и еще ну из такого
childhood in the literal sense, that is, when I
детства в прямом смысле то есть Когда я
came to
пришел в
Unaunso. And I actually, well, if my
унаунсо А я собственно ну если бы свой такой вот
path of public activism, if you can put it
путь общественного активизма если можно
that way, started with this
так высказаться начинал именно с этой
organization, then I got right into the
организации то я попал как раз ну в
Unsau faction of Korchinsky, let's
унсовскую фракцию корчинского
call it that, and Well, I'm somewhere  From 12 to 13
назовем ее так и Ну да я где-то из 12 из 13
years old, I have known this beautiful person.
лет знаком этим прекрасным человеком
Well, for me, he is a guide, a teacher, a prophet, and
это ну для меня Поводырь учитель Пророк и
all the
все
stages of the formation of the Korchynsky.
этапы становления корчинского Я из
we
все друзья Дмитрия Александровича мы мы
really gather around this
действительно сплачиваемся вокруг этой
beautiful family of Ms. Oksana, she is
прекрасной семьи Оксана это
our guardian angel - she is a
наш ангел-хранитель - это
woman devoted to an idea. And in fact, for many
предана идее женщина И собственно для многих
without women, she would have to become an example
без женщин она должна была стать примером
for imitation.  some
для подражания Я очень люблю искренне тех
time ago we are one clan We are one
нашего времени назад мы один клан Мы одна
Mafia I do not hide it on the contrary I am
Мафия Я этого не скрываю наоборот
absolutely absolutely I am
абсолютно абсолютно
proud of this and we published Dmytro
я Я с этим горжусь и мы выдавали Дмитрия
Oleksandrovich and we will publish Dmytro
Александровича и будем выдавать Дмитрия
Oleksandrovich and nothing is better than
Александровича и ничего лучше книги
Dmytro Oleksandrovich's books and his
Дмитрия Александровича его и его
philosophy and his own view of life
философия и его собственный взгляд на жизнь
in our  I don't find the time, so it's an
в нашем времени я ну не нахожу поэтому для
honor for me to carry the flag
меня почетно нести флаг
of this philosophical school,
вот именно этой философской школы
which was founded and started by Dmytro Oleksandrovich.
которую основал начал Дмитрий
What we do, from the
Александрович собственно Что мы делаем мы из
book publishing side, we cover all the
книгоиздательского фланга прикрываем все
needs of the
потребности
brotherhood, we cover all the needs of
братства прикрываем все нужды и
Dmitri Oleksandrovich of this family, and
Дмитрия Александровича этой семьи и
we try to
стараемся как можно динамичнее
spread our common philosophy as dynamically as possible.
распространять уже нашу общую философию
life is our common worldview, the
жизнь наше общее мировоззрение то
worldview that is
мировоззрение какое
most clearly formulated in the texts of
наиболее отчетливо сформулирован в текстах
General Oleksandrovich and in his own
Генерала Александровича и в его собственное
actions. Because here I have a very big
действиях Потому что здесь я очень большой
stereotype that Dmytro Oleksandrovich is, well,
стереотип что Дмитрий Александрович это ну
only there, a cabinet person, a writer,
исключительно там кабинетный человек писатель
not
нет
in the literal sense, he is just an incredibly
в прямом смысле он просто невероятно
modest person, this is connected with his
скромный человек это связано с его
Christian worldview, but I know better than anyone
христианским мировоззрением но я как никто
else about how Dmytro Alexandrovych went and when he fought, what
другой знаю о том как идет и когда воевал
things he did,
Дмитрий Александрович какие вещи он делал
what kind of
какой
fighting spirit he instilled in the
скажем дух комбативности он внушал в
hearts of young people, what feats
сердца молодых людей, на какие подвиги шли
these young people went to and Well, that's why we look at
эти молодые люди и Ну поэтому мы смотрим на
Dmytro Alexandrovych not only as  there they
Дмитрия Александровича не только как там
write that a person, yes, but it is also a
пишут что человека да но это также и
practitioner, it is a warrior, it is a person who is involved
практик это воин это человек причастный
in the history of the creative process
к истории творческого процесса
in such a metaphorical sense,
в таком как метафорическом смысле
if we use such philosophical
если использовать такие философские
concepts. Well, he really is a teacher for us,
понятие Ну он действительно для нас является учителем
so I wish you a cleaner Dmytro Oleksand and to
поэтому чище на Дмитрий Александр хочу и
all our colleagues and all our
всем нашим коллегам
brothers  from the fraternity, a
всем нашим собратьям из братства
huge greeting and eternal memory to all
огромное поздравление и вечная память всем
the dead, you probably know that
погибшим вы наверняка знаете что
very recently
совсем недавно погибли
the veterans of the fraternity died. I knew these people, they
ветераны братства Я этих людей знал это
were very bright guys and died a
были очень светлые ребята и погибли
heroic death defending Ukraine in the
героической смертью обороняя Украину на
temporarily occupied territories
временно оккупированных территориях, которые
controlled by Russia, this Cossack death is
контролируются Россией это казацкая смерть
dignified and proper  it also reflects
достойна и она собственно отражает также и
our philosophy, they died in
нашу философию они погибли в
accordance with the way they thought and
в соответствии с тем как они думали и
professed their ideas, this is an imitation of the
исповедовали свои идеи это подражание
Pannadyn principle of living as you
сковородинского принципа жить как
preach and preaching as you live, that's
проповедовать и проповедовать как жить
how I am, in principle, I don't
поэтому как-то так я в принципе я не так не
undertake to classify Dmytro
берусь классифицировать там Дмитрия
Korchevskyi there. It seems to me that this is precisely
корчевский Мне кажется это как раз вот
Ukrainian  a modern philosopher,
украинский философ современности с ними
someone agrees with them, someone disagrees,
кто-то соглашается кто-то не соглашается
but in my opinion, it carries quite a
но вот По моему мнению он несет достаточно
deep meaning, that's what
глубокие смыслы так вот то чего сейчас не
many people in Ukrainian society lack right now.
хватает многим в украинском
and you
что-то глубокое это уже единицы так и вот но
know that I have noticed people who
знаете что я вот заметил людей которые
pile up or don't pile up and throw in
наваливают или не наваливают а обвиняют
deep meanings, they are often called
глубокие смыслы очень часто называют
provocateurs, so when you
провокаторами так Вот когда ты что-то
say something that does not fit into the everyday life of a
говоришь то, что не вписывается в обыденность
walking stomach, you are immediately a
вот ходячего желудка Так ты сразу
provocateur. So I consider this to be the case when
провокатор Да я это считаю так что когда
a person is forced  to think and to think It is
человека заставляют думать а думать
difficult for many, so a person immediately
тяжело для многих так человек сразу
shouts that it is a provocation and so on.
кричит что это провокация и так далее
during the Revolution of Dignity, it
там уже во время Революции достоинства модно
was fashionable to be a provocateur there, there were
было там быть провокатором там наклейки
chevron stickers, there newspapers published a provocateur,
шевроны там газеты выдавали провокатор
for us, a stage was already passed,
это уже для нас ну был пройден этап
this metaphor is so chewed up, this is also an
столь пережеванная эта метафора это и
image, we are at the beginning of zero.
образ мы это в начале нулевых И еще и в
What is
провокативности я скажу так что ну
provocation? For us, it has more of a
провокация Для нас у нее более такой
metaphysical undertone. Provocation
скажем метафизический подтекст провокация
is a driver of progress. Without provocation,
- это двигатель и прогресса без провокации
a person cannot get out of the comfort zone, and
человек не сможет выйти из зоны комфорта
therefore only inconveniences,
следовательно, развиваться только неудобства
only non-standard situations
только нестандартные ситуации Только что-то
can develop.  you are in the role of a
повесткой дня вот оно может вы в роли
locomotive of some internal
локомотива каких-то внутренних
transformations and development of a person, therefore,
трансформаций и развития человека поэтому мы
every day we provoke ourselves to pray,
каждый день себя провоцируем на молитву
every day we provoke ourselves to a feat, every day we provoke
каждый день провоцируем себя на подвиг
ourselves to do sports, every day we provoke ourselves to do some
себя провоцируем на то чтобы сделать какую-нибудь
small good deed.
маленькое доброе дело
Well  we live by provocations, for us it is
Ну мы живем провокациями для нас, это уже
like an
ну как е-е
element of our genetic code, an element of DNA without
элемент нашего генокода элемент ДНК без
provocation. We would probably have turned
провокации Мы видимо чтобы превратились бы
into an infusoria of a shoe, even there we would
на ее инфузорию туфельку еще там
have sunk to the level of chordae
опустились до уровня хордовых
provocation, as the Marxists said that work
провокация как марксисты говорили что труд
turned a monkey into a man, well, we
сделала из обезьяны человека да ну мы
believe in something like that  another formula and
исповедуем несколько такой другую формулу и
we say that provocation made a
говорим что провокация сделала из
person out of such a
человека из такого
chewing animal semi-animal
е-е жующего е-е животных полу животной
creature created a personality, therefore it is
существа создала личность назад
impossible to go from an
невозможно пройти путь от
organic animal person to
органического животного человека до
a personality if we do not
личности если Мы не е-е
use provocative
используем при этом провокационные
methods and means  provocations, you and I are
методы и именно средства провокации я с вами
enough if we are on the same wave,
достаточно если бы на одной волне
personality,
личность
let’s say with a capital letter, it is the product of
скажем с прописной буквы она является выплодом
such a rather painstaking work on oneself
такой достаточно кропотливой работы над собой
means of provocation Well, in fact, we
средствами провокации Ну и собственно мы этот
also strap this principle to
принцип также как страполируем на
social and political reality and
общественно-политическую е-е действительность и
believe that if a nation wants to have some
считаем что если нация хочет иметь какие-то
expressive facial features, if the nation and
отличительные черты лица если нация и
society wants to have some kind of general
общество хочет иметь какое-то общее
historical claim, then it is
историческую претензию это обязательно
necessary to
нужно
use provocative methods,
использовать провокационные методы
well, Ukrainians are not bad at all lately, they
ну украинцы что-то неплохо в последнее время
are producing quite good results in
довольно неплохие результаты дают на
this field.
этому поприщу мы благодарны и
December 1 is not a national holiday, we
национальный праздник 1 декабря мы
celebrate it as St. Grader's Day, uh,
отмечаем этот день святого грейдера е-е
wonderful events took place on the bank in
прекрасные события на банке произошли в
2013 and Well, everything happens, and as we
2013 году и Ну все происходит и как мы вот
actually talked about it back in the 90s,
собственно об этом говорили и еще в 90-х да
as Dmytro Oleksandrovich wrote about it,
как об этом писал Дмитрий Александрович
then one  of the future
поэтому тогда один из будущих кандидатов в
presidential candidates, he wrote a statement on
президенты написал кажется заявление на
Korchynskyi, it seems that
корчинского что
Korchynskyi's statements, but I remember that there was
заявления корчинского но помню что был
Vunzo, and even in the days of UNSO,
вонце и еще во времена УНСО был достаточно
such a quote existed
популярный такой цитатный экзистент е-е
among the Nosov public, he had a
среди носовской публики он имел е-е
crazy demand, and Well, there is the
безумный спрос и Ну там
very first quote and  in this small
первая цитата и в этом маленьком
edition, it is such a pocket book for the
издании это такая карманная книжечка на
first quote, it sounded like
первую цитату она е-е звучала как
provocation, repression, revolution,
провокация репрессия революция
there is nothing here. There is nothing to add, provocation,
здесь вот нет Что добавить провокация
repression, revolution, full stop, but this is
репрессия революция и точка а вот такое
possible. It is a philosophical question, do
можно так философский вопрос или нет
you not consider yourself as a book publisher, a
считаете ли вы себя как книгу издатель таким
missionary, a preacher?  as in
миссионером проповедником вот как в
the Middle Ages some preacher came to
средневековье приезжал какие-то
people who, let's say, were completely unaware of
людям которые скажем совершенно не знали о
some teaching so hostile. Perhaps even
какое-то учение так враждебному Возможно даже
the environment preached like this at the risk of
среду так проповедовал с риском
their lives and so on, don't
своей жизни и так далее вот не считаете ли
you consider this activity as a preacher, that
вы эту деятельность это как проповедник чтобы
you enter as if into a foreign
вы входите как будто в чужеродное
environment and  impregnate him with
среда и оплодотворяете его вот
ideas that are right in your opinion,
правильными по вашему мнению идеями
well, clearly, the missionary component
ну однозначно миссионерская составляющая В
is present in our comprehensive work and, well, it is
нашей комплексной работе она присутствует и
not possible otherwise, we use
е-е ну иначе нельзя мы пользуемся
the methods that were developed by the
теми методами, которые были выработаны
apostles, the apostles of the
апостолами
church of the early
апостолами церкви раннего
Christian period and the
христианского периода и
disciples of Jesus Christ, so
учениками Иисуса Христа назад
here I am again  to a
здесь опять-таки Я возвращаюсь к
beautiful fragment of one of
прекрасного фрагмента одного из интервью
Dmytro Oleksandrovich's interviews, when a journalist
Дмитрия Александровича когда журналист на
asked in all seriousness how many
полном серьезе спросили сколько вот
members of your party the Brotherhood Dmytro
членов вашей партии Братство Дмитрий
Oleksandrovich
Александрович
answered enough 12. That is,
ответил достаточно 12
we do not hide the fact that we
мы не скрываем того, что мы собственно
use the methodology of the apostles as a
методологию апостолов используем как
very
вот очень
effective means to achieve our
эффективное средство для достижения своих
ideas, therefore missionary  the activity is also
идей тому миссионерская деятельность также
inherent to us, we consider it
нам присущ свойствами считаем за
necessary to appear in new environments
необходимо появляться в новых средах
to preach our ideas, that is why prayer meetings are held in
проповедовать свои идеи поэтому проходят в
our environment
нашей среде
and we have
и молитвенные собрания и проходят у нас
meetings just at which Dmytro
собрание прямо на которых Дмитрий
Oleksandrovich preaches.
Александрович
people gather around people, all people are quite
людей собирается все люди достаточно
difficult and
непростые и
have a special internal consistency.
имеют особую внутреннюю консистенцию
Therefore, missionary work is quite a
Поэтому миссионерство это довольно-таки
winning strategy, and we also bet on it
выигрышная стратегия и мы на нее тоже
from your dream plans.
ставим вот из ваших планов мечт Что бы вы
that I
считали блин ну это прямой кайф это то что
wanted to publish for years, but it didn't work out, but I saw that there
хотел выдать годами и вот не складывалось а
is such a book that you
вот видов вот есть такая книга какую бы вы
would like to realize. Well,
хотели реализовать
actually, given the specifics of my
Ну я собственно учитывая специфику своего
current life, I distanced myself a little
нынешней жизни Немножко да
from the book publishing sphere.
дистанцировался от книгоиздательской сферы
my whole
служба в армии она если бы заняла все мое
life and I
жизнь и я немножко так особенно
put my book activity on pause a little bit,
книжную деятельность поставил на паузу
but to
но
play with the
играть до
topic of what I would like to publish Well,
темы вот что хотелось бы издать
in fact,
на самом деле
I would Frankly, I would like to further
я бы Честно говоря хотел бы дальше
push the topic of the Ukrainian Latin alphabet and
проталкивать тему украинской латинки и
publish Well, very modern, relevant
выдавать Ну вот очень современные актуальные
texts in the
тексты уже именно
Vladinka coordinate system because  this is the
властинской системе координат потому что за этим
future and we have to trade this path,
будущее и е-е надо торговать этот путь
I feel that I am simply needed in
я вот чувствую что я просто ну нужен
this field,
этому поприщу и
even though it is difficult, although
хоть и сложно хоть и
in this sense I am
меня в этом смысле там достаточно
supported by a small number of people, but I
небольшое количество людей поддерживает но я
have to carry this cross.
должен тащить этот крест Ну вот как-то ну
already My
это такой уж Мой
personal emphasis My personal emphasis in
личный ударение Мой личный акцент в
this activity and as for the texts, well, there are
этой деятельности относительно текстов ну текстов
actually a lot of texts, an incredible
на самом деле очень много невероятная
number of texts that uh, we would like to
количество текстов которые е-е мы хотели бы
publish, and I would Frankly speaking, uh,
выдать и я бы Честно говоря е-е
more broadly I would look at this problem and
шире Взглянул бы на эту проблему и
admit that we  I would like to
признался бы в том, что нам бы хотелось бы
publish
выдавать
translations, and
переводы и
we would, actually, this is not only about the
нам бы собственно это не только касается
iron dad publishing house, but
издательства железный папа Но других
we are very lacking in
издателей нам очень не хватает
translated literature from other publishers. Actually,
литературы переведенной И собственно и
Ukrainian literature should also be translated
украинскую литературу следует переводить
and exported abroad in order to rebroadcast
и экспортировать наружу, чтобы ретранслировать
its meanings and its view on those historical
свои смыслы и свой взгляд на эти исторические
processes that are taking place where And actually
процессы происходящие где И собственно
their view of history, their
свой взгляд на историю
interpretation of the
свою интерпретацию
historical past, and actually spreading
исторического прошлого И собственно распространять
their politics of memory, yes, this is what the
свою политику памяти да это то что
katsaps do,
делают [ __ ]
they quite actively export
они достаточно активно наружу экспортируют
their politics of memory abroad, and because of this they
свою политику памяти и поэтому там
have
имеют
some supporters in Western Europe.
каких-то сторонников Западной Европе
We know that there are quilters in Germany  in
Мы там знаем что есть [ __ ] в Германии в
Italy, well, in many countries, there are certain
Италии ну во многих странах есть определенные
such circles of quilters that grow in the
такие кружки ватников Растущие на
Russian e-e
русском е-е
European right-wing milieu of
Европейской правой среде
quilters in the left Russia invests not
ватников в левом Россия она вкладывает не
only in the far-right, it invests in
только в ультраправых она вкладывает
general Russia invests in extremists in order
вообще Россия вкладывает в экстремистов для
to unravel the existing
того чтобы разгадать существующий порядок
world order, they need chaos and anarchy  in order
миру им нужен хаос и анархия для
to shake the established system of
чтобы поколебать сложившуюся систему
order and, against the background of this house,
порядка и чтобы на фоне этого хауса
act as a prominent
выступить в роли какого-то выдающегося в
stabilizer in quotation marks, the
лапках стабилизатора
logic of Russia is very clear and it
логика России очень ясна и она уже
can already be predicted in advance, it can be traced
ну заранее ее можно предсказать
and laid down.
проследить и прокладывать назад
right-wing extremists and
каких-то там правых экстремистов и в
left-wing extremists and religious
левых экстремистов и у религиозных
extremists. And here are all the destabilizing
экстремистов И вот все дестабилизирующие
factors, starting from the drug mafia, from
факторы начиная от наркомафии от
supporting drug trafficking to international
поддержки наркотрафика к международному
terrorism, they are of interest to Russia, and Russia
терроризма они интересуют Россию и Россия
works in these directions, it spares no
по этим направлениям работает она не жалеет
expense in order to invest
газовых стрекоз для того чтобы инвестировать
there with the goal I outlined  I
туда с очерченной мной целью я и вот
just announced that they need total
как только озвучил им нужная тотальная
destabilization, chaos in the existing
дестабилизации хаос в существующей системе
coordinate system, so if the logic in Russia
координат тому ну если бы логика в России
already exists in advance,
заранее уже есть Понятно А если она есть
it is clear.  Well, there are
козыри главное – это понимать потому что даже в
not a lot of them, but there is an
Ну не малочисленные но там
environment of some kind of youth and an
среда какой-то молодежи да
extreme orientation, e.e. Who,
экстремийского толка е-е
for example, do not cut
например не нарезают дупля которых в них
a hole that they are used in their interests by katsaps. Yes, there are public organizations that also do not cut a hole in the sense that they are
нарезают дупля в том плане что их
used by katsaps, katsaps can
используют [ __ ] [ __ ] могут
throw  money to some
подбрасывать деньги каким-то там е-е
extremist groups there, at the same time
экстремийскими кружками в то же время
they can throw dragonflies there,
они могут там подкинуть стрекозы
for example, to some human rights
например каким-то правозащитным
organizations there, Freedom House, not through
организациям там Freedom House не из-за
intermediaries, so that they raise some
посредников чтобы они подняли какие-то
debatable issues in society and
обществе дискуссионные вопросы и
split Ukrainian society there on the
раскололи украинское общество там на
topic of gender and LGBT. That is, well, they are the
теме гендера и ЛГБТ То есть Ну да они это
same  they are ready to give money to everyone. Who would want to
же они всем готовы давать деньги Вот кто бы
work for some kind of
Ладен работать на какую-нибудь отаку
divisive water,
раскольническую воду
and finally, what advice do you have? And
и вот давайте напоследок какой вы совет И
in general, what kind of wishes would you
вообще Какое пожелание широкое
convey to a wide Ukrainian audience?
украинской аудитории передали
I would advise you to remain irredeemably optimistic.
неисправимыми оптимистами я бы посоветовал бы
constructive
лелеять в себе конструктивное
dissatisfaction with oneself
недовольство собой
because it is also a powerful spring for the
как это также мощная пружина для
internal progress of
внутреннего продвижения
justified personal criticism. A person
обоснованной критики личного человека
who is satisfied with himself is not ready to
которая удовлетворена собой она не готова
leave his comfort zone. Therefore, he is a person of
выйти из зоны комфорта Поэтому е-е человек
such a normative type. I am talking about psychotype
такого норматического типа Я по психотипу
not according to some
говорю не по какой-то там генетической
genetic formula, but actually  according to
по генетической формуле, а собственно за
some inner spirit of the inner
каким-то внутренним духом внутренней
atmosphere, that is, a person of a
атмосферы так вот человек
Norric orientation should
норрического толка она должна
be guided by
руководствоваться
dissatisfaction with himself, criticize himself,
недовольством собой критиковать себя
ask himself uncomfortable questions before
задавать себе неудобные вопросы перед тем
going to sleep in a crib or in a
как лечь в кроватке уснуть или в
sleeping bag.
спальнику кто как где засыпается уже
to criticize, to get out
неудобные вопросы критиковать выходить
of the comfort zone and to develop, to
из зоны комфорта и развиваться
master foreign languages, to strive for
овладевать иностранными языками стремиться к
something constructive, because
какого-то конструктива потому что
many historical problems are
много исторических проблем они
caused by the fact that
вызваны тем что
we as a
мы
nation, in principle, had such a
как нация в принципе имели достаточно такой
long period of artificially
длительный период
created recessive way of
искусственно созданный рецессивный порядок
thinking, that is, our thinking is critical, it
мышление есть наша мысль критическая она
was in a state of decline and recession
находилась в состоянии упадка и рецессии
it  you need to
оно нужно
pray, you need to
молиться нужно
focus on some
ориентироваться на какие-то
metaphysical things,
метафизические вещи
implement an internal dialogue with yourself and
внедрить внутренний диалог с собой и
fight, fight, fight and do not give up.  we
бороться бороться воевать и не сдаваться
will continue to work, unfortunately, we will have to deal with
большое сострадание будем иметь дело с
losses and deaths,
потерями с гибельями
but unfortunately, this cannot be avoided,
но ну к сожалению этого невозможно избежать
but the victory is already here. Therefore, we must rejoice and
но победа уже есть. Поэтому надо радоваться и
work on its materialization. Thank you
работать над ее материализацией
very much. Dmytro
Спасибо очень большое с нами был в гостях
Savchenko, the head of the publishing house, the
Дмитрий Савченко руководитель издательства
iron dad and a fighter of the da
железный папа и боец ​​подразделения да
Vinci unit, was with us as a guest.  of the volunteer Ukrainian corps
Винчи добровольческого украинского корпуса
Right Sector Thank you very much, Mr. Dmytro,
Правый сектор Очень спасибо господин Дмитрий
such a conversation is quite interesting, you know
довольно интересный такой разговор живой знаете
how it is always not just the body that speaks, but the
как вот всегда говорит не просто тело а
soul that speaks, so today I have a
говорит душа так и вот я сегодня
great pleasure from the conversation, I
огромное удовольствие от общения
think the audience too Well, they will write how they
думаю зрители тоже Ну напишут как они
perceived this conversation Thank you, glory to
восприняли этот разговор Спасибо Вам слава
Ukraine and Thank you  Andrii, thank you very much for the
украине и Спасибо Андрею очень спасибо за
interesting questions and I am mutually very symmetrically
интересные вопросы и взаимное очень симметрично
satisfied with our communication, I did not
доволен нашим общением я не
use paper as at the
использовал бумажки как на заседании
office meeting, I just communicated without
бюро просто собственно общался без
filters and as much as possible. Simply, in fact,
фильтров и максимально Просто на самом деле
every live conversation has a
каждый вот живой разговор Она имеет ценность
higher value than some kind of paper reading,
выше чем какое-то вот бумажное чтение
so that’s good.
так что хорошо Все тогда
date
До свидания